# SHAIKH ABDUL QADIR

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

**\( +92 333 7115017** 

abdulqadirshaikh101@gmail.com

shaikhabdulqadir.github.io

Experienced Full Stack Developer with 4 years in the industry and high-level proficiency in the following programs: **PHP(Laravel), Javascript,VueJS, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and DevOps(AWS)**. My experience involves building scalable server side web apps. I am very familiar and experienced with Web Application Architecture and have worked with a good number of successful development teams.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Feb 2021 - Present

#### BOTSIFY INC, KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Developed back-end components to connect applications with web services. Wrote server-side and client-side code for projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript, specifically with Laravel framework.
- Using tech stack of Laravel MVC Framework, Php, MySql, PostgreSQL, Git, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.

#### **APPLICATION LAMP ENGINEER**

Dec 2019 - Jan 2021

#### NEXT GENERATION INNOVATIONS, KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Developed back-end components to connect applications with web services. Wrote server-side and client-side code for projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript, specifically with Laravel framework.
- Using tech stack of Laravel MVC Framework, Php, MySql, PostgreSQL, Git, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2017 - November 2019

#### BOTSIFY INC, KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Backend development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing against W3C.
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using VueJS & other libraries.
- Working in a data analyst role and with business intelligence applications
- Documenting features, technical specifications & infrastructure requirements.
- Working with a multi-disciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.
- AWS/DigitalOcean Server management / deployments of products.

# **EDUCATION**

## **NED UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY**

MS, INFORMATION SECURITY

Jan 2019 - May 2021

#### **SUKKUR IBA UNIVERSITY**

BACHELORS DEGREE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

August 2013 - May 2017

# **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS





















# PERSONAL PROJECTS

## **Functions Code**

https://functionscode.com

Laravel MySQL Javascript HTML Bootstrap

Functions Code is the public community for developers to share functions of different programming languages

## **Github Editor**

https://github-editor.com

VueJS Javascript Rest APIs Semantic UI

Github Editor is basically a sublime format code editor for GitHub repositories, use Github Editor to see any GitHub repository code in the editor instead of doing back and forth of web pages.

## CodeinCloud

https://codeincloud.com

Laravel MySQL Javascript HTML Semantic UI VueJS

CodeinCloud is the comprehensive IDE on the cloud by which you can connect your Live Servers through SSH Connection and and your hosting directories with FTP access and Enjoy the Live Developments with beautifully designed code

## **APIsHub**

https://apishub.com

Laravel | MySQL | Javascript | HTML | Bootstrap | VueJS

Github Editor is basically a sublime format code editor for GitHub repositories, use Github Editor to see any GitHub repository code in the editor instead of doing back and forth of web pages.

# **REST Client APIsHub (Chrome Extension)**

https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/rest-client-apishub/dabkfpeebkikmgdianbkchblbdibbfhl

VueJS | Javascript

Rest Client APIsHub is a Chrome Extension for testing APIs

# **REST Client APIsHub (Firefox Extension)**

https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/rest-client-apishub/

VueJS Javascript

Rest Client APIsHub is a Firefox Extension for testing APIs